"NictionalTreasure3" by Alex Vincent & Tyler Gatta

[Opening Line]

When play begins:
	say "Emerging in a drunken hangover from a wild party last night, you wake up in your king size bed in your extravagant apartment you walk up and go into your bathroom. Looking into the mirror you see a handsome slightly stubbled face. You are Nicolas Cage.  [Paragraph Break] In the kitchen sink you notice a letter, it's signed from your agent. You read it aloud [Paragraph Break]'Nic, I can't do this anymore. You've taken too many film roles and I feel like I'm selling out by just being associated with you.  In the past decade you haven't taken one decent role! I feel like I'm the only one who believed you could change, you know, take up a reality TV show or something. But no, you're at rock bottom. Worst of all, you've gambled away all your savings and that fucking casino! Bah, whatever. You're probably too drunk to even read this.  The bottom line is I'm through playing your mother. You've disappointed me for the last time, Cage. I quit . [Paragraph Break] 'He's right' you say to yourself. You're getting old and the bank account is beginning to run dry. What could  you do to change your agent's mind? [Paragraph Break]As you turn around you notice a National Treasure poster hanging above your bed. 'GATES!', you yell. [Paragraph Break] 'I'm going to write National Treasure 3'.  ".

[**RULES**]
A thing is either encrypted or decrypted.
A room is either discovered or undiscovered.  A room is either an entrance or a main.
Instead examining an encrypted thing: 
	say "[description][line break]";
	say "This object might contain hidden markings.";
	
Instead of asking Jon about something:
	[say "(Asking a specific character) [noun] - [the topic understood] - [the player's command][paragraph break]";]
	if the topic understood includes "paper": 
		say "'Jon, would you take a look at this clue I found?' you ask. [paragraph break]Jon examines the revealed message and replies, 'Ahh yes, the Land of Oil. Legend has it that Meriwether Lewis and William Clark were not an expedition simply to explore the West, but were actually in search of a hidden treasure. I never greally bought into it, but this note came from the President's Book of Secrets, so maybe you're on to something. I reckon you should pay a visit to the wax museam in Hollywood and check out what they have on Lewis and Clark.";
	else if the player's command includes "clue": 
		say "'Jon, would you take a look at this clue I found?' you ask. [paragraph break]Jon examines the revealed message and replies, 'Ahh yes, the Land of Oil. Legend has it that Meriwether Lewis and William Clark were not an expedition simply to explore the West, but were actually in search of a hidden treasure. I never greally bought into it, but this note came from the President's Book of Secrets, so maybe you're on to something. I reckon you should pay a visit to the wax museam in Hollywood and check out what they have on Lewis and Clark.";
	else if the player's command includes "oil": 
		say "'Jon, would you take a look at this clue I found?' you ask. [paragraph break]Jon examines the revealed message and replies, 'Ahh yes, the Land of Oil. Legend has it that Meriwether Lewis and William Clark were not an expedition simply to explore the West, but were actually in search of a hidden treasure. I never greally bought into it, but this note came from the President's Book of Secrets, so maybe you're on to something. I reckon you should pay a visit to the wax museam in Hollywood and check out what they have on Lewis and Clark.";
	else:
		say "Jon replies, 'Not sure about that... Do you have any leads for another treasure?'"
		
Instead of examining Wax Clark:
	say "There's nothing interesting about Clark. His placard reads 'Clark was was the lesser known of the two.  Clark was there to provide moral support - kind of like Robin to Batman. Nobody really cares about him beyond that.'".
Instead of examining Wax Lewis:
	say "You notice Wax Lewis is carrying a compass and decide to touch it. Upon touch, it immediate falls, but your Cage-reflexes quickly catches it. Upon closer examination of the compass, you discover it's just a fake replica. Damn it! That can't be all. In all of your Cage-rage, you notice the placard next to Wax Lewis. It reads [Paragraph Break] 'Lewis was brains behind the expedition. Carrying the compass, now located in the Smithsonian, Lewis discovered what would later be the entire rest of the United States. In his journal he wrote, It was just sitting there, the entire west portion of the United States. I'm surprised I was the first to find it.'[Paragraph Break] The Smithsonian? I guess that's where you'll need to head next.";
	now the player has the wax compass.
	
Instead of going to the Smithsonian Upper Hall:
	if the player is wearing the mask:
		say "Right this way, sir.";
		move the player to Smithsonian Upper Hall;
	else:
		say "I'm sorry mister Cage, but this is a restricted area".
		
Instead of examining the bookshelf:
	if PassageDiscovered is false:
		say "You pull a book on the bookshelf releaving a hidden passage in the center of the room. Cage's clue sense are tingling. Maybe you should head down there.";
		now PassageDiscovered is true;
	else:
		say "The bookshelf had a secret level that opened a passage way! Cage's clue sense are tingling. Maybe you should head down there.".
		
Instead of going to the Luxurious House Basement:
	if PassageDiscovered is false:
		say "You can't go that way.[Paragraph Break]";
	else:
		say "You crawl down the dusty opening and into a secret candle-lit basement filled with sprawling notes, books, journals and posters";
		move the player to the Luxurious House Basement.
		

[**REGIONS/ROOMS**]

[Las Vegas Region]
Las Vegas is a region. Bedroom, Lobby, and The Strip, The Garage are in Las Vegas. 
Bedroom is a room. The printed name of Bedroom is "Las Vegas Home Bedroom".  The description of the Bedroom is "There is a lobby to the north."
Lobby is a room. The printed name of Lobby is "Las Vegas Home Lobby". The description of Lobby is "The Strip is east of here." Lobby is north of Bedroom. 
The Strip is a room. The Strip is east of Lobby.
The Garage is a room. The Garage is west of the Lobby. The motorcycle is in the garage. The motorcycle is fixed in place. A cabinet is in the garage. A cabinet is a closed container. Inside the cabinet is a seven dollars.

[Hollywood/Wax Museum Region]
Hollywood is a region. Hollywood Sign, Hollywood Boulevard are in Hollywood.
Hollywood Sign is a room.
Hollywood Boulevard is a room. Hollywood Boulevard is south of Hollywood Sign.
Wax Museum is a region. Wax Museum Lobby is in Wax Museum.
Wax Museum Lobby is a room. Wax Museum Lobby is east of Hollywood Boulevard.
Wax Museum West Hall is a room.  Wax Museum West Hall is a west of Wax Museum Lobby.  Wax  Oprah is in the Wax Museum West Hall. Wax George Clooney is in the Wax Museum West Hall.  Wax  Angelina Jolie is in the Wax Museum West Hall. 

Wax Museum East Hall is a room. Wax Museum East Hall is east of Wax Museum Lobby. Wax John Travolta is in the Wax Museum East Hall. Wax Kim Kardashian is in the Wax Museum East Hall.  Wax Micheal Jackson is in the Wax Museum East Hall. 

The steel trapdoor is a door. Wax Museum Storage is a room. Wax Museum Storage is below the steel trapdoor. The steel trapdoor is below the Wax Museum Lobby.  The steel trapdoor is locked. The wax museum key unlocks the steel trapdoor.  The wax museum key is in the Wax Museum Storage. Wax Lewis , Wax Clark is in the Wax Museum Storage. Wax George Bush is in the Wax Museum Storage. Wax Tom Cruise is in the Wax Museum Storage.

[Indian Reservation]
Indian Reservation is a region. Grassy Field and Old House Porch are in Indian Reservation.
Grassy Field is a room.
Old House Porch is a room. Old House Porch is north of Grassy Field.

[Somewhere in Texas]
Somewhere in Texas is a region. Luxurious House is in Somewhere in Texas.
Luxurious House Porch is a room. Luxurious House Living Room is a room. Luxurious House Living Room is north of Luxurious House Porch. Luxurious House Bedroom is a room.  Luxurious House Bedroom is west of  Luxurious House Living Room.  Luxurious House Bathroom is a room. Luxurious House Bathroom is east of Luxurious House Living Room. Luxurious House Basement is a room.  Luxurious House Basement is below Luxurious House Bedroom. 

[Gettysburg]
Gettysburg is a region. Gettysburg Front Lawn is a room. Gettysburg Cemetary is in Gettysburg.


[Times Square]
Times Square is a region. Times Square Center, North Times Square , South Times Square, East Times Square, West Times Square  are in Times Square.
Times Square Center is a Room.
North Times Square is a room. North Times Square is north of Times Square Center.
South Times Square is a room. South Times Square is south of Times Square Center.
East Times Square is a room. East Times Square is east of Times Square Center.
West Times Square is a room. West Times Square is west of Times Square Center.

[Smithsonian]
The Smithsonian is a region.
Smithsonian Lobby is a room.
Smithsonian Main Hall is a room. Smithsonian Main Hall is north of Smithsonian Lobby.
Smithsonian Upper Hall is a room. Smithsonian Upper Hall is above the Smithsonian Main Hall.
Smithsonian Upper Corridor is a room. Smithsonian Upper Corridor is west of Smithsonian Upper Hall.  Smithsonian Upper Balcony is a room. Security Breakroom is west of Smithsonian Upper Corridor. Security Breakroom is a room. Smithsonian Upper Balcony is east of Smithsonian Upper Hall.
Smithsonian Security Room is a room. Smithsonian Security Room is north of Smithsonian Upper Corridor.
Smithsonian West Wing is a room. Smithsonian West Wing is west of Smithsonian Main Hall. 
Smithsonian East Wing is a room. Smithsonian East Wing is east of Smithsonian Main Hall.
Smithsonian Safe Room is a room.  Safe Door is a locked door. Safe Door is north of Smithsonian East Wing. Safe Door is south of Smithsonian Safe Room. The description of the Safe Door is "It's a solid meter of steel that doesn't have a key lock. It probably opens electronically from somewhere. But where?"

The computer is inside the Smithsonian Security room. The description of the computer is "you can probably hack safe door from here, but it looks like you'll need a password to get in the system as to not rouse suspicision.". 

[NullRoom - this is for storing secret objects . The player shouldn't have access to this room]
NullRoom is a room.

[**OBJECTS**]

[Objects in Bedroom]
A bed is in the bedroom. "A king sized bed with silk sheets takes up most of the room." The description of the bed is "The bed is still unmade from last night's escapades." The bed is fixed in place.
A spray bottle is an object. The description of the spray bottle is "The bottle is full of lemon juice. Handy for finding clues."
A torn out paper is an encrypted object. The description of torn out paper is "It's the Page 47 from the president's secret book in National Treasure 2." 
A mask is an object.  The description of the mask is "It's a mask of John Travolta you stole from the Face/Off set. It's waxy accuracy to JT is eeriely similar". The mask is wearable.
A  declaration is an object. The printed name of declaration is "Declaration of Independence (declaration)". The description of declaration is "You went back and stole this a second time after the filming of National Treasure 2."
A nightstand is a closed container in the bedroom. "There is a nightstand by the side of the bed." The nightstand is openable and fixed in place. The description of the nightstand is "An ancient Greek nightstand where you keep your most valuable treasures." The declaration, torn out paper, and the spray bottle are in the nightstand. 
A dresser is a closed container in the bedroom. "An exotic African dresser is also pushed up against the wall on the other side of your bed". The dresser is openable and fixed in place. The description of the dresser is "An old voodoo dresser said to once be a magical dresser that enchants clothing items." The mask is in the dresser.

[Objects in Smithsonian]
A glass case is in the Smithsonian Safe Room. The glass case is a container.  Inside the glass case is the ancient compass. The description of the glass case is "This is where the Smithsonian keeps the Lewis and Clark compass! The security alarm looks like it can be spoofed if you can keep something of equal size and weight in the glass case at all times".

[Objects at Bush's House]
A bookshelf is in the Luxurious House Bedroom. 

[Objects in NullRoom]
An ancient compass is an object. The description of the ancient compass is "It's scrateched bronze coat comes off at your fingertips. This must point the way to the lost land of Oil! For some reason, it seems to point to ... somewhere in Texas? Maybe you should follow it."
A security outfit is in the NullRoom. The description is "It's a kinky police officer outfit. I'm sure this might get me in the backdoor somewhere ( ͡° ͜ʖ ͡°)."
A wax compass is in the NullRoom. The description of the wax compass is "It looks identical to the one Lewis and Clark used in weight and size, but it's nowhere near the real one."

[**PEOPLE**]
Nick is a person. The printed name of Nick is "Nicolas Cage". The player is Nick. The description of Nick is "You are Acadamy Award winner, national-treasure-finder,  and panty-dropper, Nicolas Cage."
Nick is in bedroom.
Street Salesman is a person. The description of the Street Salesman is "It looks like he's selling a lot of knock-off film role outfits. He's selling a kinky police outfit for 10 bucks".  

Jon Voight is a person. The description of Jon Voight is "He played the role of your father in the first two National Treasure movies." Jon Voight is in The Strip.

[**VARIABLES**]
SprayCapacity is a number variable. SprayCapacity is 100.
PassageDiscovered is a truth state that varies. PassageDiscovered is false.

[**SCENES**]
Preparation is a scene. Preparation begins when play begins. Preparation ends when SprayCapacity is 90.

[**ACTIONS**]
Replacing is an action applying to one thing. Understand "replace [something]" as replacing.
Carry out replacing:
	if the noun is Wax John Travolta:
		say "You quickly hide the Wax Travolta behind a curtain and, wearing your mask, take its place. You wait until closing as a security guard puts you into a box and hauls you down into storage. You quickly burst out, finding yourself in the Wax Museum storage.";
		move the player to Wax Museum Storage;
	if the noun is ancient compass:
		say "You stealthily replace the compass with the wax one you found at the museum and put the real one in your pocket.";
		now the wax compass is in the glass case;
		now the player has the ancient compass;
	else: 
		say "Cage probably wouldn't do that. Maybe in a different film".
		
Hacking is an action applying to one thing. Understand "hack [something]" as hacking.
Carry out hacking:
	if the noun is the computer:
		say "You enter the password and unlock the door downstairs";
		now the Safe Door is unlocked.
		
[Region Travel]
[Hardcoded traveling, because it's the only way to move between regions]
Travelling1 is an action applying to nothing. Understand "travel to The Smithsonian" as travelling1.
Understand "travel to the smithsonian" as travelling1. Understand "travel to smithsonian" as travelling1. Understand "travel to Smithsonian" as travelling1.
Carry out travelling1:
		move the player to the smithsonian lobby.
		
Travelling2 is an action applying to nothing. Understand "travel to Las Vegas" as travelling2.
Understand "travel to las vegas" as travelling2. Understand "travel to vegas" as travelling2. Understand "travel to Las vegas" as travelling2. Understand "travel to Vegas" as travelling2. 
Carry out travelling2:
		move the player to the lobby.
		
Travelling3 is an action applying to nothing. Understand "travel to Hollywood" as travelling3.
Understand "travel to the hollywood" as travelling3. 
Carry out travelling3:
		move the player to Hollywood Sign.
		
Travelling4 is an action applying to nothing. Understand "travel to gettysburg" as travelling4.
Understand "travel to Gettysburg" as travelling4. 
Carry out travelling4:
		move the player to the gettysburg front lawn.
		
Travelling5 is an action applying to nothing. Understand "travel to The Reservation" as travelling5.
Understand "travel to the reservation" as travelling5. Understand "travel to reservation" as travelling5. Understand "travel to Reservation" as travelling5.
Carry out travelling5:
		move the player to the Grassy Field.

Travelling6 is an action applying to nothing. Understand "travel to texas" as travelling6.
Understand "travel to Texas" as travelling6. 
Carry out travelling6:
		move the player to the Luxurious House Porch.

Travelling7 is an action applying to nothing. Understand "travel to Times Square" as travelling7.
Understand "travel to times square" as travelling7. Understand "travel to Times square" as travelling7. Understand "travel to times Square" as travelling7.
Carry out travelling7:
		move the player to the Times Square Center.


Understand "spray [something]" as spraying. Spraying is an action applying to one thing. 
Check spraying: 
	if the player does not have the spray bottle, instead say "You need a spray bottle to do this.";
	if the noun is decrypted, instead say "Don't waste your juice.";
Carry out spraying: 
	if the noun is torn out paper and SprayCapacity is 100:
		now the description of declaration is "Note to self: [line break] 1. Ask Jon about the land of oil.";
	now the noun is decrypted;
	now SprayCapacity is SprayCapacity minus 10;

		
Report spraying: 
	say "You spray ([SprayCapacity]% remaining) the [noun] with lemon juice to reveal a secret message: ";
	if noun is torn out paper:
		say "[line break]'The American people have been lied to. America is not the land of prosperity, it’s the land of oil. Somewhere under this sacred land was buried millions of gallons of oil - oil to power a million hummers for a thousand years.  I will find it, with or without the help of the FBI.'";
		say "[line break] You think to yourself, 'I better go to The Strip to ask Jon Voight about this clue.'";
	else:
		say "Default message, replace with clue";




